Benn Tan Mobile: 91714744 Email: btjm123@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Hello! I am a budding software engineer with a ferocious passion for imagination, inventiveness sustained innovation. I find myself drawn towards the infectious sense of entrepreneurial zest, deep creativity and high technical expertise common in Silicon Valley. I am especially passionate about the rapidly-evolving fintech, blockchain and defi industry; I hope to make my mark in the industry in the future

EDUCATION

National University of Singapore

Yet to matriculate

- Computer Science
- Offered NUS Merit Scholarship

Victoria Junior College

Jan 2019 - Dec 2020

- Integrated Programme (IP)
- Straight As for 4H2 content subjects
- Edusave Certificate of Academic Achievement / Good Progress Award (SGD300)

EXPERIENCE

Ascent Tech Full Stack Engineer

Dec 2020 - Apr 2021

- Assembled a team of highly-skilled engineers
- Focused on using iterative development to transition from a basic MVP to a high-performant, high-impact application built on robust and scalable microservice architecture
- Developed an autonomous employee monitoring system to identify sources of organizational slack and inefficiency
- Website Link

DrinksGoWhere Software Engineer Intern

Jan 2021-Feb 2021

- Developed an automated workflow to transfer high volumes of messy data on bars menu to formatted csv files with Node.js
- Link(

SGExams Backend Engineer

Mar 2020 - Dec 2020

- Streamlined a seamless database migration workflow from PostgresSQL to MongoDB
- Responsible for the development and maintenance of the SGExams server
- Website Link (received over 5000 signups)

AWARDS

Singapore Games Creation Competition

May 2017 - Sep 2017

- Achieved overall Merit Award
- Initiated the development of a 2D-platformer game that includes a boss level with basic artificial intelligence, using GMStudio and GML to raise awareness of environmental conservation

Singapore Games Creation Competition

May 2018 - Sep 2018

- Obtained overall Commendation Award
- Created a fast-paced game (which is a hybrid of a 2D-platformer and a shooting game) with GMStudio and GML to raise awareness of the importance of one's mental and physical health

Cyber Defenders Discovery Camp by DSTA (Brainhack)

June 2019

- Achieved 1st runners up in the JC Category
- Exposed to and solved several types of cybersecurity problems (cryptography, programming, OSINT, blind SQL injection etc.)

YouthHacks Hackathon Nov 2019

- Obtained 2nd runners up in the Open Category
- Designed a Telegram chatbot that utilizes DialogFlow API to offer an engaging Al-based conversational interface and Firebase as the backend that renders different types of assistance (computational intelligence with Wolfram Alpha API, homework reminder etc.) to students today

National Olympiad in Informatics Qualification Contest

Apr 2020

- Highest scorer in VJC and ranked 41st nationwide
- Solved a problem utilizing Fenwick Trees (for logarithmic updates and queries) and dynamic programming (to accelerate computation of factorials) with C++

CO-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Victoria Junior College V-Hack

July 2019 - present

- Co-founder & Vice-President
- Championed an initiative in VJC to bring together like-minded people who are passionate and knowledge about computer science
- Created learning resources and conducted programming lessons on an ad-hoc basis for curious young minds

Access Victoria 2020 – present

- Actively involved in this student-led initiative which offers a platform for peer mentoring in VJC
- Currently a H2 Chemistry mentor, as well as the Subject Coordinator for the whole Chemistry department, where I oversee all the Chemistry mentors and mentees
- Administered the transfer of the high volume of signups on this platform (150+) from Gmail (web scraping)
 to Notion (converting the data into a CSV file) utilising jQuery and Node.js

PROJECTS

iOS Drawing Application

2016

- Launched a <u>YouTube channel</u> (that has amassed over 98k views) to impart knowledge of iOS development to people through real-life software projects
- Developed with CoreGraphics and UIKit library through Swift 3 and XCode IDE
- Github Link

Platform of go.vjc.sg

2019

- Kickstarted development of the front-end of a website using HTML, CSS and jQuery for animations to introduce VJC's V-Hack Society
- Website Link

V-Hack Website 2020

- Developed an internal application that consolidated basic information of students and incorporated FacePlusPlus API for facial recognition services
- Created an <u>online judge</u> for V-Hack Society to automatically grade code submissions in a secure sandbox environment with JudgeO API against a set of pre-defined test cases
- Developed with Node.js, npm, Express, MongoDB, EJS and hosted with DigitalOcean, nginx (for reverse proxy) and Namecheap for domain